welcome back to another shotcut video
欢迎回到另一个截图视频
editing tutorial in this video we're
编辑教程在这段视频中我们
going to be learning how to apply a
将学习如何应用
filters and effects to your video clips
视频剪辑的滤镜和效果
so to get started I'm just going to
所以在开始之前 我只想
bring in a video clip I've got one here
带一段视频剪辑进来 我这里有一段
on my computer we'll just do this one
在我的电脑上 我们只做这个
right here so it starts playing the
就在这里 它开始播放
video I can pause it by pressing the
视频我可以通过按下
spacebar and to do so right now we have
空格键 要做到这一点 我们现在
the playlist opened up but that's just
播放列表打开了 但那只是
for me your layout might be different it
对我来说 你的布局可能有所不同
seems like different versions have
看起来不同的版本
different things there's these tabs at
不同的东西有这些选项卡在
the bottom we've kind of touched on a
我们已经触及到的底部
little bit so filters is one of the tabs
一点 所以过滤器是选项卡之一
and it it's just called filters you
这就是所谓的过滤你
apply a filter to a video clip either an
将滤镜应用于视频剪辑
audio filter or a video filter and that
音频过滤器或视频过滤器 以及
will produce an effect there are certain
一定会产生一定的效果
filters for like cropping and resizing
用于裁剪和调整大小的滤镜
and rotating there's filters for color
旋转的时候有滤色器
there's filters to increase the audio so
有过滤器可以增加音频 所以
it's called filters in shot cuts another
它被称为镜头中的滤镜另一个
way to get to filters is to click up on
访问筛选器的方法是单击
the filters at the top and it just does
顶部的过滤器 它就是这样做的
the same thing it brings up the same
同样的东西 它带来了同样的东西
thing as if you just click on the
就像你只需点击
filters tab and like we've kind of
筛选器选项卡 就像我们拥有的
talked about in the past if we left
如果我们离开 过去说过的
click on this filters we can actually
点击这个过滤器 我们可以实际
move it to a different part of the
将其移动到
interface and then if it gets closed and
接口 然后如果它被关闭 并且
we click filters again up top it just
我们在顶部再次点击过滤器
appears where it last was at so you just
出现在它最后一次出现的地方 所以你只需要
know that yours might not be exactly
要知道你可能并不完全是
where mine is these tabs can trade
我的位置在哪里这些标签可以交易
places
地点
but the filters tab is where we get to
但是过滤器选项卡是我们要进入的地方
all the effects okay so to add an effect
所有的效果都可以 所以要添加一个效果
we actually just click on this plus sign
我们实际上只需点击这个加号
and so it brings up by default all these
因此 默认情况下 它会带来所有这些
favorites and then you can search by
收藏夹 然后您就可以按
just video effects and just audio
只有视频效果和音频效果
effects in this video we're just going
这个视频中的效果我们只是
to be covering the video effects so just
为了报道视频效果 所以
to show you kind of what's going on here
向你们展示这里正在发生的事情
we're gonna add like this color grading
我们要添加这样的颜色分级
one all we do is just left click on it
我们所要做的就是左键点击它
and it applies the filter and so then we
它应用了过滤器 所以我们
can change some of the settings for this
可以更改此的某些设置
filter we can adjust some of the
过滤器我们可以调整一些
coloring so this is like an extreme
上色 所以这就像是一个极端
coloring we've done and actually if you
我们已经完成了上色 实际上如果你
notice I'm applying this to a clip in my
请注意 我将此应用于我的
source so it's not really applied but
来源 所以它并没有真正应用 但
there's not really anything in the
在那里没有任何东西
timeline it's just showing me what this
时间线它只是在告诉我这是什么
would look like and then if I add this
会是这样的 然后如果我加上这个
down to the timeline it adds it in with
一直到时间线 它将它添加到
this effect applied to it
这种效果适用于它
another thing we can do here well just
我们在这里能做的另一件事就是
show you actually if we just split this
展示给你看 如果我们平分这个
right now we click this button here and
现在我们点击这里的按钮 然后
we split it into two separate clips both
我们把它分成两个不同的夹子
clips have the effect applied to it
剪辑具有应用于其的效果
because any any clip that has a filter
因为任何带有滤镜的剪辑
at effect applied to it will just keep
在效果上应用于它将只保持
that even if it becomes split or moved
即使它变得分裂或移动
around so if you want to increase the
因此 如果您想要增加
audio for example which we'll cover in
例如音频 我们将在
the next video you would increase it on
在下一个视频中 您将增加它
the entire clip you bring in before
你之前带进来的整个片段
making any edits or cuts to it but now
对其进行任何编辑或裁剪 但现在
that these are separate now we could
它们是分开的 现在我们可以
change them we can change and have them
改变他们 我们可以改变并拥有他们
be different colors so now we have you
不同的颜色 所以现在我们有了你
know the red and then the green
先知道红色 然后知道绿色
something to pay attention to as well
还有一些需要注意的事情
whatever clip is selected is the one
无论选择哪一个剪辑 都是
you're going to be editing effects for
你要编辑的特效是
not the clip that's being viewed so
而不是正在观看的剪辑
right now we're on the project tab we're
现在我们在项目标签上 我们正在
viewing what's in our project we can hit
查看我们的项目中可以点击的内容
spacebar and play it and we're looking
空格键 然后玩它 我们正在寻找
at this green here but if we want to
在这个绿色的地方 但如果我们想
come over and change the color and make
过来换一下颜色 然后做一个
it a little bit more red we move over
它变得更红了 我们走过去
here and nothing's happening well that's
在这里 什么都没有发生 这是
because even though we're looking where
因为即使我们在寻找
our playhead is at the clip that's
我们的播放头在这段视频里
selected is this one over here so we're
被选中的是这里的这一个 所以我们
making changes to that one we're just
对那个做些改变 我们只是
not viewing the changes that we're
没有查看我们正在进行的更改
making if you want to see what we're
如果你想知道我们在做什么
changing while we're changing it we have
在我们改变它的同时 我们拥有
to move the playhead over here to the
将播放头移到这里
clip that's selected and now when we
选定的剪辑 现在当我们
make changes it'll you know it'll show
做出改变 你知道它会显示出来的
in there if we want to we can add
在那里 如果我们愿意 我们可以添加
multiple effects at once if you want to
如果您想要一次产生多个效果
apply another effect over top of this we
在此之上应用另一种效果
just click the plus sign again and we
只需再次单击加号 我们就可以
can add like a blur maybe
也许可以像模糊一样添加
and so the blur has different settings
因此 模糊具有不同的设置
obviously because it's a different
很明显 因为这是一种不同的
effect a different filter and so this
效果不同的滤镜 所以这
one we can just make the whole thing
我们可以把整件事都做好
really blurry and just get kind of crazy
真的很模糊 变得有点疯狂
with it and now we have this kind of
现在我们有了这种
blurry colored video also you may have
你也可能会有模糊的彩色视频
noticed it's kind of slows down the more
注意到它的速度越慢
effects we add and depending on your
我们添加的效果取决于您的
computer specs it'll it may not render
计算机规格它可能不会呈现
as quickly and in playback like right
就像在回放中一样快和正确
now
现在
but when we actually export the video
但当我们实际导出视频时
it'll be full speed it won't have that
它会全速前进 不会有那样的情况
lag enos to it if we find maybe we want
如果我们发现也许我们想要 就把enos放在后面
to get rid of the this blur effect and
为了摆脱这种模糊效果
go back we can just click the minus
返回 我们只需点击减号
button and it gets rid of whatever one
按钮 然后它就会去掉任何一个
selected let me bring back another one
选中了让我带回另一个
note so that we have to cuz I want to
注意 所以我们必须 因为我想
show you something else we can do like
向你展示一些我们可以做的其他事情
this glow one maybe so it adds a glow
这个发光的可能是为了增加光泽
you can kind of see what it's doing and
你可以看到它在做什么
to kind of and if we want to see exactly
如果我们想确切地看到
what it's doing we can just check the
它在做什么 我们只需检查
box to the to the left of it right now
方框就在它的左边
it's checked if we uncheck it it takes
如果我们取消选中它 它将被选中
the effect off but it still keeps it
效果消失了 但仍然保持了它
over here under you know so we can take
在这里 你知道的 所以我们可以
this off and see what our original looks
把这个脱掉 看看我们原来的样子
like without actually deleting the the
如 而不实际删除
filter or the effect that we're we're
滤镜还是我们是
using so I'm gonna check both of these
使用 所以我要检查这两个
we can see what it looks like and so
我们可以看到它是什么样子的 所以
sometimes maybe you want to just see
有时候你可能只想看看
what it looks like before you started
你开始之前的样子
doing the covering but then when you go
做封面 但当你走的时候
to export you just check this and make
要输出您只需检查此选项并制作
sure that they're all applied I've
我确信它们都被应用了
reloaded this clip and I've cleared out
重新加载了这个剪辑 我已经清空了
all the filters and I actually brought
所有的过滤器和我实际上带来的
in four more Clips because I want to
在另外四个片段中 因为我想
show you another feature we can do with
向您展示我们可以使用的另一项功能
these filters and that is copying a
这些过滤器 也就是复制一个
filter and applying it to multiple Clips
筛选并将其应用于多个剪辑
so welcome back here to this first one
欢迎回到第一个节目
we'll just go add and we can just type
我们只需要添加 然后我们就可以输入
in up here too so there's one called
在这里也是如此 所以有一个叫
like film grain or film dust it's this
就像胶片颗粒或胶片灰尘 就是这个
old film just like this old film look
老电影就像这个老电影的样子
I'll apply this it's really small here
我来涂这个 这里真的很小
but I'll make it a little bit bigger and
但我会把它做大一点
extreme just to kinda show you know
极端的只是为了展示你知道的
illustrate what's going on here whoa so
说明这里发生了什么 哇 所以
now we play we see all this kind of film
现在我们玩 我们看所有这样的电影
dust happening on there go back and if
发生在那里的尘埃回到那里 如果
we want to apply this to multiple Clips
我们希望将此应用于多个剪辑
we can just come over here while we have
我们可以趁我们有空的时候过来
the clip selected that has the filter
具有滤镜的选定剪辑
applied to it we hover over and there's
应用到它 我们盘旋在上面 有
this icon that says copy the filters we
这个图标上写着复制我们的过滤器
click copy and that'll actually copy all
单击复制 这实际上将复制所有
the filters we only have one applied so
我们只应用了一个过滤器 所以
it doesn't really matter but it does
这真的不重要 但它确实重要
copy all of them to be aware of that and
复制所有这些文件以意识到这一点
then we'll come over here to this next
然后我们接下来就到这里来
clip that doesn't have any filters and
没有任何滤镜的剪辑和
then hit the paste icon and now this one
然后点击粘贴图标 现在是这个
should have the same filter with the
应该具有与
same settings that we gave it so it
与我们给它的设置相同 所以它
gives it a consistent feel across all of
给人一种一致的感觉
it we come to this one do the same thing
如果我们来到这里做同样的事情
come to this one do the same thing and
来到这里 做同样的事情 然后
now our whole project is going to have
现在我们的整个项目将会有
this old film look to it
这部老电影看起来很像它
and so that's a way that you can apply
所以这是一种你可以申请的方式
multiple filters if you do have split up
多个过滤器 如果有拆分的话
in different clips but you want to all
在不同的剪辑中 但你想要所有
have the same filter like there's a good
有相同的滤镜 就像有一个好的
one - that's like white balance that you
一-这就像是白平衡
use pretty commonly so for white balance
通常用来达到白平衡
if you're if all your clips are shot the
如果你是 如果你所有的片段都被
same day in the same location but you
在同一地点的同一天 但你
want to have them have a consistent look
想让他们拥有一致的外观
you can adjust the white balance
你可以调整白平衡
accordingly and oops
相应地 哎呀
that was not oh we had we applied white
那不是哦 我们涂了白色的
balance to this one is that that's an
这一次的平衡是 这是一个
example of something what I was talking
我所说的事情的例子
about just not to do where we were
关于不做我们当时的事情
making changes to the clip without
对剪辑进行更改 但不
looking at it so this is the white
看它 这是白色的
balance here that we can see make it you
我们可以看到这里的平衡让它成为你
know much warmer or much colder anyway
无论如何 知道更热或更冷
hopefully you found this video
希望您找到了这个视频
informative in the next one we're gonna
下一个我们将提供信息
talk more about filters and specifically
更多地谈论过滤器 特别是
applying audio filters and working with
应用音频过滤器并使用
audio in our timeline so hopefully found
我们时间轴中的音频希望能找到
this informative go ahead and play
这个信息丰富的继续玩吧
around filters I don't forget to Like
围绕过滤器我不忘记点赞
comment subscribe leave your questions
评论订阅留下您的问题
below and I'll catch you in the next
在下面 我会在下一个找到你
video
视频